Mss.Rec.25 Mss.Rec.25
American Philosophical Society
Tewa Recordings
1957
Mss.Rec.25
American Philosophical Society
3.0 Reel(s)
Music and interviews recorded by the anthropologist Gertrude Kurath in 1957 at Santa Fe and San Juan Pueblo, New Mexico, now known by its earlier name, Ohkay Owingeh. The recordings contain group singing performances of Deer Dance Songs, Yellow Corn Dance Songs, Butterfly Dance Songs, and interviews on these songs and general Tewa music and dance terminology with primary consultant, Antonio Garcia. Additional Deer Dance Songs given by David Garcia.
3 sound tape reels (2 hr., 15 min.): analog, 7 1/2 ips, full track, mono; 7 in.
Garcia, Antonio
Garcia, David
Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Presented by Gertrude Kurath in 1957. This material was recorded with the assistance of a Phillips Fund grant.
Related Archival Materials
Related Tewa manuscript material by Kurath can be found in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics (Mss.497.3.B63c.)
San Juan Pueblo (N.M.)--Songs and music; Sound recordings; Tewa dance; Tewa Indians--Music; Tewa language
- Audio recordings
  - Deer Dance Dawn Song Set 1, by group, 1957-02-27; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:44; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    San Juan Pueblo (N.M.); San Juan Pueblo (N.M.)--Songs and music; Tewa Indians--Music; Tewa language
  - Deer Dance Dawn Song Set 2, 1957-02-27; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:36; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
  - Deer Dance Dawn Song Set 3, 1957-02-27; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:08:38; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
  - Daytime Deer Dance Songs in Plaza, 1957-02-24; 1957-03-24; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:17:30; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    Scope and Contents note
    Songs recorded at earlier date at San Juan Pueblo interspersed with interview recorded at Santa Fe at later date on translation of the songs.
    San Juan Pueblo (N.M.); San Juan Pueblo (N.M.)--Songs and music; Santa Fe (N.M.); Tewa Indians--Music; Tewa language
  - Postlude, 1957-02-24; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:41; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    Comments on translation of San Juan Pueblo and importance of maintaining them. Tape cuts off before completion of comments.
    San Juan Pueblo (N.M.)--Songs and music; Santa Fe (N.M.); Tewa Indians--Music; Tewa language
  - Interview on Deer Dance texts, 1957-02-24; 1957-03-24; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:21:57; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
    Interview conducted at Santa Fe at later date includes songs played back on tape that were recorded at earlier date at San Juan Pueblo.
    San Juan Pueblo (N.M.); San Juan Pueblo (N.M.)--Songs and music; Santa Fe (N.M.); Tewa Indians--Music
  - Yellow Corn Dance Songs and text interview, 1957-02-24; 1957-03-24; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:16:19; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
  - Yellow Corn Dance Songs straight - group, 1957-02-24; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:32; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
  - Butterfly Dance Songs and interview, 1957-02-24; 1957-03-24; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:52; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Garcia, Antonio; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
  - Deer Dance Songs, 1957-02-24; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:09:40; Garcia, David; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch
  - Interview on general music and dance terminology, 1957-02-24; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:28:26; Garcia, Antonio, Jr.; Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch; Kurath, Hans, 1891-1992
    San Juan Pueblo (N.M.)--Songs and music; Santa Fe (N.M.); Tewa Indians--Music